Well.
글쎄요
Hello there everybody.
안녕하세요, 여러분
I am so grateful that you've made it through to the start of week seven.
7주 차까지 살아남아서 정말 다행이에요
It is tremendous and I plan to not disappoint.
정말 굉장하네요 실망시키지 않을 거예요
I will make it worth your while.
보상은 충분히 해드리죠
It's going.
가고 있어요
There's some really great content ahead.
정말 멋진 콘텐츠가 기다리고 있어요
You may be feeling a bit of an anti-climax from what happened last week with our disappointing results.
지난주 실망스러운 결과로 비트가 좀 가라앉았을 거예요
Fine tuning frontier model after so much hype.
과대광고 끝에 미개척 모델을 다듬었어요
But what I can tell you is it's like a good movie where there's a period of time where things feel tense
하지만 긴장되고 실망스러운 시기가 있는 좋은 영화와 같다는 건 말씀드릴
and disappointing.
수 있어요
There's going to be redemption, there's going to be redemption.
구원을 받을 거예요 구원을 받을 거예요
We will see if you're like me and you kept hammering away after after those results, you will have,
저처럼 계속 노력하는지 두고 봐야죠 결과를 보고도 어느
I expect, got to a point where you have got some improvements.
정도 나아졌는지 확인할 거예요
You get to a point where you can fine tune and actually get better results than we originally got with
미세 조정으로 원래의 비튜니티 버전보다 더 나은 결과를
the Untuned version, but not significantly so, but a little bit better than I did in the last day.
얻을 수 있는 지점에 이르렀죠 큰 차이는 없지만 어제보다 약간 나아졌어요
But anyways, for now we are moving swiftly onwards.
어쨌든 지금은 빨리 진행할게요
We are launching into week seven and what a week do I have in store for you?
이제 7주 차예요 어떤 주를 준비했다고 했죠?
Uh, it is a massive week.
엄청난 한 주예요
It is a really massive week.
정말 중요한 한 주예요
It is an advanced week where we're raising the bar.
기대치를 높이는 한 주예요
We're getting to a point where you're now acquiring advanced skills in this kind of deep learning field
llm의 딥 러닝 영역에서 고급 기술을 습득하는 단계에
of of llms.
이르렀죠
And as we move more deeply into training, what you can already do, of course, you can already generate
훈련에 더 깊이 들어가면 이미 할 수 있는 건 프론티어 모델, API
text and code with frontier models, with APIs, and with hugging face open source code.
페이스 오픈 소스 코드로 텍스트와 코드를 생성할 수 있어요
You can build rag pipelines and then you can now build data sets.
래그 파이프라인을 만들 수 있고 데이터 세트를 만들 수도 있어요
Quite a long time we spent on data sets and baseline models and frontier models that you can fine tune,
데이터 세트와 기준 모델 개척 모델에 꽤 오랜 시간을 투자했어요 미세 조정할 수 있는
albeit with not amazing results.
모델이라 결과가 좋진 않았죠
For our use case today we get advanced.
오늘 유스케이스는 Get 케이스예요
We talk about using a technique called Lora for fine tuning open source models.
로라라는 기술을 이용해 오픈 소스 모델을 미세 조정하는 거죠
We describe quantization.
퀀타이즈를 설명할게요
We talk about Q Laura, and we're getting into three key hyperparameters R alpha and target modules,
Q 로라에 관해 얘기하면서 세 가지 핵심 하이퍼파라미터 R 알파와 표적 모듈에 관해 얘기할 겁니다 처음 마주치는
which if you've not encountered them before, sounds like something straight out of Star Trek, but
거라면 스타트렉에서 튀어나온 것 같지만 오늘 저녁이면
in fact will make complete sense by the end of today.
완전히 이해하게 될 거예요
And before we launch into it, I do need to take a moment to remind you of your eight week plan, and
시작하기 전에 8주간의 계획을 다시 한번 짚고 넘어가죠 지금 이 시점에서는 지루하게
this may feel like this is boring for you at this point, but I think it's important to take pride in
느껴질 수도 있지만 자신의 성취에 자부심을 갖는 게 중요하다고 생각해요 모든
your accomplishments and to remember where everything that you've learned, you started.
걸 어디서 배웠는지 어디서 시작했는지 기억해야 하죠
When we we first had our session to talk about, uh, uh, the, the opportunity with Llms and Frontier
처음 모였을 때 Lms와 프론티어 모델에 대해 이야기하고 두 가지를 비교했습니다.
models and we compared them, um, we then looked at using the UIs, we use Gradio, we used agent ization
UI 사용도 살펴보고 그래디오와 에이전트 Iization 다중 모듈도 사용했죠.
Then we got to hugging face the pipelines and then Tokenizers and models.
그다음은 페이스 더 파이프라인 포옹 토큰라이저와 모델이었죠
Then in week four, we generated code by selecting LMS for the task.
4주 차에는 LMS를 선택해 코드를 생성했죠 작업을 위해서요
In week five, that was rag week.
5주 차에는 엉망이었어요
We used the wonderful Chroma and Lang chain to build some rag pipelines there, and hopefully you did
크로마와 랑 체인을 이용해 랙 파이프라인을 지었어요 프로젝트를 맡아주셨으면 해요
the project, which I'm really excited to see what people do there.
사람들이 거기서 뭘 할지 정말 기대돼요
Uh, and then last week we fine tuned a frontier model.
지난주에는 개척 시대 모델을 미세 조정했어요
Uh, now you know how to do it.
이제 어떻게 하는지 알죠?
You understand about creating the data sets.
데이터 집합을 만드는 걸 이해하죠
You know how it works, and you understand when it's most applicable, when you're dealing with that
어떻게 작동하는지 알고 언제 가장 적합한지 알죠 그런
kind of nuance of tone, and perhaps when it's not so applicable, in our case, when you're trying
뉘앙스를 다룰 때요 우리 경우에 별로 적합하지 않을 때는 기능성을
to actually build in functionality because a frontier model is already so massive.
구축할 때죠 프런티어 모델은 이미 너무 크니까요
Um, so now we arrive at week seven, we are going to be fine tuning an open source model, one that
이제 7주 차인데 오픈 소스 모델을 미세 조정할 거예요 프론티어 모델보다
is significantly smaller than a frontier model, and see where we get to with that.
훨씬 작은 모델이죠 어떻게 되는지 보죠 get it
And week eight is where it all comes together.
8주 차부터 모든 게 합쳐지죠
And so with that introduction, the main topic of the day is Laura, and we will launch right into that.
이 소개로 오늘의 주요 주제는 로라입니다 바로 시작해 보죠